guess what everyone i have been enjoying
my netherite armor and my netherrite
tools
but my old nemesis
the snow
is back
you can see all the bits that i missed
with string and
i was pretty sure that i'd got all of
this so i'm gonna do a bit of tidying up
today
and we are also going to tidy up this
area
the best we can i'd love to get a little
bit more done in here today because
like i've been saying this portal needs
to be fixed and you may also notice i
got my zoom back zoom zoom zoom
zoom
zoom you have no idea how much i love
the zoom so let's kick off today's
episode by heading to the nether i think
i think i think i found a really cool
place to make my nether base and i also
because i was getting frustrated i was
getting really lost in all of these
tunnels
i don't really know what's going on so
in order to stop my confusion i
basically made a wibbly-wobbly tunnel
that goes diagonal all the way
to the shopping district portal and i
called it
diagon alley
okay so what we want to do is head over
to the coordinates that i found and
check them out oh my goodness i just got
a piglet head oh oh goodness i'm hideous
i'm hideous hello my son the area that i
really liked was here in an open basalt
delta biome that is a real mouthful to
say and what do you know tucked away in
this basically underground part of the
nether i have found a bastion i'm not
really sure what these oh come on no no
no oh these hurt oh they hurt this is my
first time ever coming across them i
don't i also don't know if this has
already been raided or not nope
definitely hasn't that's a lot of gold i
don't remember seeing this block
it looks like a dragon scale that is so
cool oh my goodness there's a there's a
lot of pigs there's a lot of pigs
there's a lot of pigs
ah
okay that's the first disappointing
chest i've had here
oh my goodness there's a block that
looks just like me i'm pretty sure
that's meant to be like a pigs now but i
mean
do you see the difference
cause i don't i don't i don't call this
the green block gold there's just
literal gold all over this thing so this
giant structure is literally part of the
bastion oh whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa
whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa
whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa no no
no no no no no no no no no no no no no
no
that's not good
that's really not good oh
no
okay
don't panic
don't panic panic panic panic panic
panic panic fortunately i took down
where that bastion is but i'm gonna have
to make some very very quick very very
quick purchases before we go anywhere i
ran myself into a bit of a corner there
the main thing is to get back it sounded
like i lost an awful lot of items there
but the main thing is to get back the
netherright armor everything else is
replaceable i got gold to distract them
oh
okay
let's do this there it is
i got some of my stuff back all right so
there's the issue just over there how do
i do this ah at range
with a trident perfect i managed to get
the one thing that would save me here
okay
i should be
i should be all good where is my helmet
though somehow i lost my elytra and my
helmet
unless a piglet has taken it and walked
away
i think i'm going to have to come to
terms with the fact that i've lost my
lytra and
my netherright helmet somehow
and now i will be very lucky to get out
of here alive these piglens are not as
uh not as weak as i thought i panicked
my helmet
huh
yes yes yes yes
oh thank goodness
oh thank goodness okay my elytra i can
deal with the rest of it
doesn't matter i got all my netherright
gear
i thought it was weird that i couldn't
find it someone nabbed it and ran away
so
that bastion wait
why was i even in the nether i'll be
honest i've completely forgotten why i
was even here
classic
green distraction so this is a bastion
in its entirety
that could be useful to turn into a farm
since things seem to spawn there a lot
i'm gonna get out of here before this
elytra
doesn't make it
oh we made it so the nether is still
kind of scary not gonna lie when i died
i thought they had me there now
hopefully later on in this episode we
will find out
who has made it
for mayor i'll be honest with you
seeing as neither me or mumbo actually
voted for him it's quite unlikely that
mumbo actually get to be mayor now
back to the task at hand before i got
insanely distracted i don't feel like we
can actually go into the nether without
without getting lost or distracted
because there's so many new things to
find and do
so i want to head back and i want to
finish this thing over here or at least
do a bit more progress i doubt i'll
finish this in one sitting
so let's go into time-lapse mode
tidy this up and get something proper
built here
because it's uh
currently not looking great let's go
[Music]
so
it might not look like much but that
still took an enormous amount of time
and i had to stop a little earlier than
i really wanted
because it's actually time
to
find out who is going to be the next
mayor
next mayor the first mayor of the
shopping district so i've kind of had to
cut this a little bit short and this is
one of those projects
which is really taking me a long time
and i'm also finding it extremely
difficult to sit down for longer than
just a couple of hours at the moment
because i've been i've been really busy
like not just busy in minecraft making
videos but busy in real life as well so
finding a balance has been a little bit
difficult lately but we'll get there
we'll definitely get there and the other
good news before we head over to the
shopping district is that i have found
a place in the nether which is going to
be perfect
the only issue is it's a little bit far
away
and by a little bit far away
i mean over one and a half thousand
blocks away
which isn't ideal at all but there are
new and very very fast ways of traveling
in the nether now using one of the
striders those weird things on two legs
that them
and the place that i would like to claim
is here and it doesn't look like much
because it's kind of not it is a huge
and i mean huge
open area in the nether
completely surrounded
by the crimson biome it is
phenomenal this is a space which is
quite rare in the nether itself so i
will reveal that the reason i need a big
open space is because i want my nether
base to be quite big and i also want it
to hang from the ceiling downwards so
we're creating a bit of an upside down
so i'm very excited about this and i'm
also thinking about inviting a few other
people to kind of settle nearby if they
want to but look at the surroundings
here
it is absolutely gorgeous
just gotta make sure i'm stocked up on
fire potions
so that is the place that i've chosen
for my nether base and i think it's
pretty pretty cool even if you can't
really see too far
in the nether maybe there's something i
can do about that but anyway let's head
over to the shopping district because it
is time to find out who takes the
diamond throne it is time to announce
who is
the mayor so without looking at who has
voted who i want it to be a little bit
of a reveal what i'm gonna do is pop
down an empty shulker box
move this put in a hopper there and all
of those should go out there we go that
way i don't i don't know who has won
before everyone else
and i've asked all the hermits to gather
around so we can announce who
has won there we go i've got it in my
inventory but i'm not gonna look at it
now i'll do the same for the dog catcher
now we just need to wait for everyone to
gather round which they are slowly doing
welcome everybody to i guess the
announcement i think this is like the
first time i've seen this many people on
the hermitcraft server in front of me
and i'm pretty i'm pretty pleased to see
so many mustaches in the in the audience
today that's uh this bodes well right
we've actually got quite a lot of votes
to get through so i reckon we should
crack on uh first of all we're going to
announce who the winner is for dog
catcher on the hermitcraft server so i
think what we're going to do is our
readout and then if someone who is near
the candidate if they can put in the uh
concrete powder then we can get like
live results all right so uh the first
vote is for joe hills
the next one is joe hills
nice yeah good job the next one is joe
hills
fantastic
joe of the hills is there's another one
so four four votes for joe uh joe hills
that's five votes
joe six
daffy duck
who voted for daffy duck
landslide victory joe good job man
all right let's let's go so right uh
ready next to your your polling
candidate the first vote is for stress
the next one is for false oh yeah good
times with scar it took a long time to
read out all of these results so the
final results were
four votes for false five votes for
stress
ten votes for scar
and zero for mumbo jumbo that means scar
one
gigi
you won there we go congratulations
congratulations man hey hold on mumbo we
didn't get a single vote yeah no i'm
aware of that green and we haven't
talked we'll be having talks later
okay i'm so glad to take that mustache
off oh you still was ready
make the cut well i'm a little nervous a
little shaky um all right i'll be a good
man guys um
yeah
hi
dude how's it going i see that we have
returned to our end rods which means
this is a serious meeting outside of
grumble yeah this is a grump meeting um
so zero votes zero zero votes zero votes
you know this is my campaign manager and
all that
you're the candidate and all that
you didn't vote for yourself and
i mean
look
i kind of
look i i had a moment in in the booth
okay i
things came back to me okay i remembered
as i was in the booth okay i kind of had
a little bit of a panic and i realized
well hold up i didn't even want to be
mayor in the first place this was not
actually my idea i saw you
i had the same i had the same epiphany i
had the same moment of like you know
what scar might actually be a good man
and
i kind of invented you as a joke and
yeah i think we made the right decision
what's not fair though is how we've left
good old grumbot he he didn't do us he
didn't do us wrong well he kind of did
but well he did no he definitely he
definitely did do us wrong yeah he did
he did plenty wrong yeah he
he did his best
yes he tried he tried extremely hard to
his demise
of like our minds so yeah if anything
weird we're to blame but we can't we
can't leave him like this
no it's quite sad and depressing yeah we
gotta we gotta fix him up but i don't
think i can stomach telling him that you
didn't become mayor or in fact that his
two favorite dads didn't vote for him
you know what i mean
no that could be a huge problem yeah we
could end up with
uh yeah him i mean i don't even know
what would happen he's already he got
into this state because we asked him
what we're going to do on the last day
he would explode right he would just
genuinely explode he wouldn't even yeah
no responses he would just
yeah exactly it would be a huge issue so
um
i mean
what do we do do we just kind of create
a world i think we yeah yeah we take it
dude i think i think we we dress you up
as mayor we tell him you won and we we
box him in in his own little world and
and job done he's and he's just
oblivious just oblivious to the outside
world he thinks that life is going on
mumbo's mayoring everything's great
exactly and uh i think because he's
melted right now we can get away with
anything and then we'll bring him back
online once it's all set up
yeah yeah that sounds like a good plan
all right let's do it let's do it
[Music]
behold grumbot's virtual reality it's i
want to live here
i might stay here as well for the rest
of the hermitcraft season just chill out
in here it looks this is lovely i mean
it is nighttime right now but you've got
some artificial light it's always it's
always day here i think i think this is
this is a good life for him it's
certainly better than what where he was
on the on the platform of course yeah no
this is lovely uh i'm sure he's gonna be
happy with this i guess we should
probably just get him online i mean he's
now fixed up yeah we think so we fixed
we fixed him but we haven't got him
online yet because obviously you know he
we wouldn't want him online while we
were building his universe that kind of
doesn't make much sense okay so
what we need to do is basically tell him
that you've won you've won if you look
at the there's like a fake uh shopping
district island and oh yeah yeah
monument to your mustache and then we
just we just tell them that you won but
i think to to really sell it you've got
to you've got to put on like a mere mere
skin
he's not going to buy it otherwise
all right okay so what like a suit with
uh
the whole lot yeah yeah the the sash
that says mare just in case anyone was
confused so i'm gonna go full back to
being in a suit i'm just excited to be
in a suit i've had these high jeans on
now for like three months yeah i do i've
taken off i've taken off my mumbo for
mercy sheds yeah i couldn't as long as
they have gone
your support as soon as
as soon as no votes came in you're like
oh well as soon as i didn't vote for you
i was like well i can't wear this
anymore
all right well i'm gonna get my suit on
now hold on you have to take off your
armor there bud
dude
i like the business that is legit
i'm upset that i didn't vote for myself
now
you look
you look so qualified
yeah why was i
why didn't i put this on from the start
you look so qualified now
maybe it was this ridiculous outfit you
mustered the hygiene the t-shirt i'd
vote for you right now
i'd vote for myself and that's saying
something and i've got the back of my
hair back
you're a complete you're a complete mom
grumbot what that's all he needed to do
is change his skin to a nice crisp suit
with a sash
okay look let's let's stop let's get all
the negative energy out of the way
before we get him back online because
let's not
let's tell him the good news shall we
okay yeah yeah yeah do i still have to
feed him diamonds
yes this is
look okay if we ever build another
grombot right yeah
it's eating dirt next time he's at the
power
power run
the
race
oh wow he's gonna love that he's gonna
really love that he's gonna he's gonna
he's gonna flip right let's go oh man
we're bringing him back
flood the mayoral reservoir going
grumbot what do we think
yay
okay well he didn't he didn't he didn't
melt he didn't break
and there's one piece of paper which is
a that's a positive sign
that's an incredibly positive sound
do you want to check it or should i
all right grandpa's life has meaning
grandpa's life has meaning we did it
okay i think he's i think he's happy i
think he's happy but you know he seems
pleased yeah we've uh we've truman
showed him we put him in the matrix we
put him in virtual reality where you won
the race
to stop
we have to go out back
all right
[Music]
[Laughter]
what the heck no
that was mental he just dropped down and
instantly blew up like he landed in
front of my face oh no
let's go and install a little window so
we can uh we can have a little look so
we can peep on him yeah yeah yeah so we
can we can spy on him
he seems
all right oh oh you just straight up
landed
oh my goodness this is
not land
i'm here so we've got the cloud window
and he is so happy
he's the happiest he's ever been he is
the happiest grumba
i mean he's been nothing the only
emotions he's ever shown is just a
deadpan face yeah
angry yes or sad
this is the first time he's actually
this is what he was built for he was
built to make you mayor and in his world
you are the mayor you just have to turn
up every now and again to just you know
show face
dude i was gonna say is this i mean you
know it's a really really happy ending
like he is yeah he is happy illusion are
we good people i think so i think so
is this a good thing to do
yeah
yeah yeah he is he is pleased
he's dead chuffed that's what he is
he is dead
all right well okay so we've done the
right thing grumbot is saved he's all
happy he's he's that i'm i may not be
mayor but in in a small section of the
hermitcraft server you are i am there
you are and to be honest with you i
actually forgot that you're not mad
because you're wearing the most
convincing outfit i've ever seen you
know i am basically yeah this this this
gives me all mayoral rights i think i
think well done i think that's it oh
yeah job well done should we fly off
into the into the sunset or the the
sunset's the other way
yeah well you know we'll fly off into
sunset oh my goodness i forgot that i
put a face on the box
yeah i don't think that's my proudest
moment i saw the mustache i saw the cube
and i was like yeah it'd be fine i just
had some eyes
then yeah
it's a bit weird
so that kind of draws a conclusion to
the mayoral race
hopefully scar does a really good job he
has officially taken up the mantle of
the diamond throne and i wonder how big
this diamond throne is actually going to
stay
with him in charge i have a feeling he's
going to throw diamonds at a lot of
problems but who knows
but i'm afraid
that is all we've got time for today
building my base and actually building
that thing over where grumbot is it took
up most of my time for this episode i'm
not gonna lie so i think that is all we
have time for today and i would like to
next episode get started on my upside
down base but i really really need to
also finish my new nether portal so
there's there's so much to be done and
i've still got to like keep up with
stuff like this i don't even know if
i've got any sales
oh yeah there's sales there's quite a
few sales
the investment pile is getting pretty
big
but i've still got to keep up with the
shop and i've got lots of things to do
so i shall see you in the next episode
thank you very much for watching as
always and good bye
rombot's so happy we're gonna have to
have to figure out something to do with
drumbot there